DERRICK FRIMPONG

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A creative UI/UX designer with a knack for transforming complex user requirements into intuitive, engaging digital experiences. Delivered multiple high-impact projects, enhancing user satisfaction and driving significant increases in user engagement. Known for its collaborative approach and ability to seamlessly integrate user feedback into design improvements, ensuring optimal functionality and aesthetic appeal.

WORK HISTORY

IT Tutor, 03/2024 to 06/2024

Apha Morning Dew Montessori School - ACCRA

- This position is responsible for educating the students who are placed in my care.
- As a teacher, I set the tone of the classroom, build a warm environment, mentor and nurture students, become a role model, and listen and look for signs of trouble.
- Consistently arrived at work on time and ready to start immediately.
- · Carried out day-to-day duties accurately and efficiently.
- Demonstrated respect, friendliness and willingness to help wherever needed.

UI/UX Designer, 01/2022 to Current

Freelancer - Accra

- Developed wireframes and prototypes to effectively communicate design ideas to stakeholders and team members
- Collaborated with developers to implement responsive design, improving accessibility on devices creative designs
- Enhanced user experience by designing intuitive and visually appealing designs
- Consistently met project deadlines by managing time efficiently and prioritising tasks according to importance levels.
- Provided creative solutions to complex UX problems, improved customer satisfaction levels.
- Managed multiple projects simultaneously whilst maintaining high quality standards in output.

Customer service representative, 03/2016 to 08/2022 City gate ventures - Accra

- · Strong communication and interpersonal skills.
- Ability to work effectively in a fast-paced environment.
- Proficiency in Microsoft Office Suite, and basic computer skills..
- Improved customer satisfaction by effectively handling complaints and inquiries.
- Managed high volume of inbound calls for quick resolution of

CONTACT

Address: GC-137-0103 Accra, ACCRA, GHANA 00233

Phone: +233599604518

Email:

deefrimpong1994@gmail.com **Web:** derrick-designx.vercel.app **LinkedIn:** linkedin.com/in/derrick-f

rimpong-21012199

WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

 https://derrickdesignx.vercel.app/

SKILLS

- Figma
- · Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- HTML & CSS
- · User Interface
- · Responsive design
- Wireframes
- · Creative design
- Teamwork
- Collaboration
- Microsoft Office applications

customer issues.

- Ensured smooth running of operations with timely preparation of reports.
- Provided top-notch support for increased customer satisfaction.
- Answering incoming calls and messages from customers regarding products or services.

Graphic Designer, 03/2019 to 01/2020 **PALACE MALL** - ACCRA, ACCRA

- Developed creative design for print materials, brochures, banners, and signs.
- Improved client satisfaction by creating visually appealing, impactful graphic designs.
- In charge of Pizza Hut, Second Cup, AZ outlet, and Palace Mall designs.
- Produced high-quality graphics for print and digital media platforms, enhancing company reputation.
- Utilised advanced software tools for improved efficiency in graphic design production.

EDUCATION

High School Diploma, Graphics And Web Design, 12/2018

IPMC - Accra

Certificate, UI/UX Design, 06/2024

Dev&design - Nigeria

Certificate, UI/UX Designer, 08/2024

Aptlearn - Nigeria

CERTIFICATIONS

- · Aptlearn, 08/2024
- Dev&design, 06/2024

LANGUAGES

English:

HOBBIES AND INTEREST

Football